JONATHAN CLIFFORD

PHOTOGRAPHER & DESIGNER

EXPERTISE

Logistics & Project Planning

Photo Library Management

Adobe Creative Suite

Apple Systems

HTML & CSS

Wordpress

EDUCATION

MA DOCUMENTARY
PHOTOGRAPHY &
PHOTOJOURNALISM
(WITH DISTINCTION)

University of Westminster London, UK 2013 - 2015

BACHELOR OF PHOTOGRAPHY & COMMUNICATION DESIGN

Queensland College of Art Griffith University Brisbane, Australia 2005 - 2008

CONTACT

+44 (0) 7432 159 468

JMA.CLIFFORD@GMAIL.COM

JONATHANCLIFFORD.COM

PROFILE

Experienced creative professional with excellent interpersonal skills and unique problem-solving abilities, supported by diverse and extensive industry experience and a relevant post-graduate level education.

I am socially outgoing, relaxed and friendly, but in a work context, I pride myself on being punctual and hard working, always aiming to exceed others' expectations. I am self-disciplined, driven and always look to take the initiative in tackling new challenges. I thrive under pressure and have consistently demonstrated my ability to rapidly absorb new information and immediately put it into use.

A passion for travel and the desire to make a difference in the lives of others has motivated me to work as a volunteer overseas and to produce a number of self- funded photographic documentary projects highlighting important social issues.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Photographer & Designer, 2008 - Present

My photographic and multimedia work ranges from documentary projects about important social and humanitarian issues, to the production of commercial images for a variety of markets, from interiors and food, to fashion and product photography.

In previous personal projects I've explored gender issues, displacement and natural disasters. More recently my focus has turned to human rights abuses, in particular the global human trafficking crisis, which I've explored through an innovative portrait series.

Through my extensive experience as a photographic assistant to several international photographers, I have keenly developed my problem solving abilities and furthered my understanding of the technical and practical, but also the business elements of photography.

As a designer I work in a variety of areas, including large scale branding and identity campaigns for local and international businesses. My services include creation of an effective online presence, bespoke website design, integration of social media into websites and blogs, consultation on brand awareness and the use of social media.

JONATHAN CLIFFORD

PHOTOGRAPHER & DESIGNER

REFERENCES

DEBORAH MCDONAGH

Photography Course Director
Further Learning Academy
+353 86 829 2193
deborah.mcdonagh@mail.com

JAMES WHITLOW DELANO

Photographer +81 80 4674 0984 james.delano@pep.ne.jp

MARTIN ROEMERS

Photographer
Panos Pictures Agency
+31 640 536 597
martin@martinroemers.com

JEN STOREY

Workshop Co-ordinator
Foundry Photojournalism Workshop
+1 801 800 7999
jen@provo.edu

CONTACT

+44 (0) 7432 159 468

JMA.CLIFFORD@GMAIL.COM

JONATHANCLIFFORD.COM

EXPERIENCE

Photography Tutor, British Academy of Photography, April 2016 - Present

- Facilitating classes as both a lead and an assistant tutor, ensuring course material is delivered in an engaging and efficient manner.
- Responsible for providing extensive, supportive feedback to students from a diverse range of backgrounds and experience levels.
- Proofing and updating existing course materials to keep them in line with current industry standards, as well as suggesting new elements to broaden the practical and theoretical experience of students.
- Managing student questions and concerns on a personal, face-to-face level, ensuring that they are addressed with due consideration and action.

Computer Technician, Apple Inc., April 2013 - Present

- Providing technical support and troubleshooting advice on a range of personal computers and mobile devices, along with peace of mind and clarity to clients by answering their questions, calling upon an extensive knowledge of both software and hardware.
- Performing extensive hardware repairs on the full range of Mac systems, observing correct safety procedures and innovating on existing practices and processes.
- Facilitating one-to-one training sessions with clients, on a wide variety of subjects and software, ranging from advanced photo and video editing to basic functions of the Mac OS X operating system.
- Careful and consistent time management required in order to manage the significant workload and fast pace of the technical department.
- Demonstrating exceptional levels of patience, empathy and general customer service at all times and going the extra mile to add a personal touch to each and every client interaction.

SKILLS

- Excellent interpersonal and communication skills
- Strong networking skills genuine interest in building relationships
- · Enthusiastic and confident personality
- · Always seeking to develop by learning and applying new skills
- Highly self motivated to exceed expectations as well as personal targets
- · Strong team player, able to relate to people from all walks of life